Those whom he trusts
信任的
followed him into the woods.
都跟进林子了
Those whom he doesn't trust
不信任的
were left behind.
都留下了
Including you, right?
也包括你自己吧
It's normal that His Highness doesn't trust me.
世子不信我很正常
I have no loyalty to him anyway.
本来我也没什么忠心可言
Then why do you work as his guard?
那你为什么还要做他的护卫
Aren't you the same?
你不也是
Now that we're talking about it,
说起来
we all stay by His Highness's side
大家留在世子身边
to get what we want.
都是各取所需
I think
我觉得
we should scratch each other's back.
我们应该互相照应一下
The same for you as well.
你也一样
Of course, I haven't forgotten Mr. God of Sword.
我当然没忘了剑神大人
You and Xu Xiao
剑神大人和徐骁
are not related.
没有什么牵连
I guess
我猜
you escorted His Highness to the east
你护送世子东行
on certain conditions, right?
应该也是答应了什么条件吧
You were once on the top of the martial world.
剑神大人曾傲视天下
Do you know a martial esoterica named
您知不知道有门功法
White Emperor Esoterica of Simplicity?
叫白帝抱朴诀
To be honest,
不瞒前辈
I chose to serve under the Xu family
小女子投效徐家
for this very esoterica.
就是为了这套功法
If you remember this,
若先生记得这个
I'm willing to serve under you.
舒羞愿改投前辈门下
Get lost!
滚开
I'll leave you be, sir.
那就不打扰先生了
A beast passed by.
有猛兽经过
Jiang Ni.
姜泥
Is she in danger?
不会遇险了吧
I don't think so.
应该不会
Aren't you afraid that I'll tell this
你就不怕我把这些话
to Xu Fengnian?
告诉徐凤年吗
Say whatever you like.
随你怎么说
The fact that you're after something
你有想要的东西
only reassures them.
他们只会更放心
If the Lin family knows White Emperor Esoterica of Simplicity,
你们林家若是知道白帝抱朴诀
I can change side to serve under you.
我也可以为你效力
My name is Lyu Qiantang.
我叫吕钱塘
Jiang Ni!
姜泥
Are you okay?
没事吧
Look.
你看
What?
怎么了
Wow.
哇
Hukui.
虎夔
It's dead.
已经死了
I wonder what could kill it.
也不知道是什么杀了虎夔
I saw it.
我看见了
It ran over before my eyes.
从我跟前跑过去的
It didn't attack you?
它没袭击你
No.
没有
It didn't even stop,
它都没停
and ran away directly.
直接跑了
What does it look like?
长什么样
It ran too fast. I didn't see it clearly.
跑太快没看清
It was black-and-white
就看见是黑白杂色
and was carrying a person.
而且背上还背了个人
They flashed by.
一晃而过
I only saw his back.
就看见背影
The person carried a sunflower.
还扛了一根向日葵
Have you heard of such a person in the martial world?
江湖上有这号人物吗
Not really.
倒没听说过
Watch out.
小心
It isn't entirely dead.
没死透
A pregnant mother.
是母兽怀胎
And she's about to give birth.
幼兽就要出生了
What a once-in-a-million-year opportunity.
真是千载难逢的机遇
When a Hukui is born,
虎夔出生
once it opens its eyes,
睁眼
it would take the first creature it sees as its parent.
看到的便认作做父母
If you're the first person that the whelp sees,
若是幼兽第一眼看到世子
you can domesticate the beast.
便能收服此等怪兽
The female came out first.
先出来的是雌的
The male came out after.
后出来的是雄的
Sister and brother.
那就是姐弟了
They'll open their eyes soon.
它马上睁眼了
Let them see you.
让它看到世子
The mother is covered with injuries.
母兽浑身是伤
Yet her belly is fine.
唯独腹部安然无恙
It was fighting to protect her children.
它一直拼命护着这两个孩子
Grandpa Wei.
魏爷爷
Fortune and luck
天机气运
can be obtained,
都可以靠实力争夺
but a mother shouldn't be taken away from the children.
但母亲不该被夺走
Guys,
小家伙们
this is your mother.
这就是你们的娘亲
Watch her closely.
你们看好了
And remember her with your hearts.
看在眼里记在心里
Don't ever forget her.
千万别忘了
Her eyes.
它的眼睛
Your mother is dead.
你们的娘亲死了
They really treat you
还真把世子
as their family.
当亲人了
I'm not your dad.
我可不是你们爹
I'm not lying to you.
千真万确没骗你们
So unfriendly.
这么凶
Don't bite her.
这个不能咬
She's with me.
这是自己人
It's God's will.
天意使然
These two Hukui
这两只虎夔
are predestined to be with you.
天生就应该跟着世子
They need names, right?
总要有个名字吧
You're the big sister.
你是姐姐
I'll call you
那你就叫
Bodhisattva.
菩萨
You're the little brother.
你是弟弟
Your name is Vajra.
你叫金刚
The names are too difficult for them.
这哪儿能听得懂
Yeah.
对呀
Bodhisattva.
菩萨
Vajra.
金刚
They understand you.
真听懂了
The elder sister is like a mother.
长姐如母
She's teaching her brother.
这是管着弟弟呢
Can I touch them?
我能摸吗
Don't be afraid.
别怕啊
It's fine.
没事的
They have scales since little.
这么小就有鳞片了
Their mother has two horns.
它们的母亲是双角
How come they are single-horned?
它们为什么是独角呢
And they have different colors.
颜色还不一样
After they grow up, they will have two horns.
长大了就会长出双角
And their colors will change.
颜色也会变化
Your Highness,
世子
every part of a Hukui
虎夔
is a treasure.
浑身是宝
Her scales can be made into
鳞甲做成甲胄
impenetrable armor.
刀枪不入
It's no worse than Fujiang Armor.
不比伏将红甲差
Bury her.
把它埋了吧
You want nothing?
什么都不要
She gave me her children.
它把两个孩子托付给我
And that's enough.
足够了
Let's go.
出发吧
Which way?
怎么走
We travel across Qingcheng,
越过清城
and use the waterway.
改走水路
We float down the river and head straight to Qingzhou.
顺江而下
Get into the carriage.
上车
Where did you get the baby Hukui?
哪来的小虎夔呀
Very ballsy of you.
倒是有胆气呀
What are you looking at?
看什么
A fine sword.
好剑
Xu Xiao said,
徐骁说了
he can't hold a sword.
不能给他剑
Your mother's Daliang Dragon Sparrow.
你娘的大凉龙雀
You recognize it?
这你也看出来了
Don't be nervous, little girl.
小丫头你别紧张
The sword has been used by a woman for too long.
这剑女娃子用久了
It doesn't suit me.
不适合我
won't you say goodbye to your aunt?
你不去跟你姑姑道个别吗
I've said what I needed to say.
该说的都说过了
Travel east on the water,
水路东行
and you'll reach Qingzhou.
便是青州
Beware of the Lord of Jing'an Zhao Heng.
千万小心靖安王赵衡
In North Liang,
在北椋时
I learned what he's capable of.
我已领教过他的手段
When the late emperor passed away,
当年老皇帝过世
his eight sons fought over the heirship.
八龙夺嫡
The Lord of Jing'an almost
靖安王只差了少许
got to sit
便能坐上
in the throne.
至尊之位
He's a scheming
此人心机深沉
and resourceful man.
经纬韬略
He's no worse than the emperor of Liyang.
未必就输给离阳的皇帝
Don't worry, aunt.
姑姑放心
As long as North Liang still has the 350,000-man army,
有北椋三十五万大军在
Zhao Heng wouldn't dare to kill me.
赵衡不敢杀我
I hope so.
希望如此
All the businesses of the Lin family in Qingzhou
林家在青州的产业
are under control.
今时已经全在掌控之中
The financial data
这其中财务的流转数目
is all written in the books.
都全写在这儿
My lord,
王爷
(Account Book) would you take a look?
要不要过过目啊
It's kind of a shame.
说起来也可怜哪
Such a large family
好大的一个家门
was ruined.
被毁于一旦
I wonder
也不知道如今
how many people in the Lin family still live in the world.
林家还剩下几人存活于世啊
I'm on it.
王某正在追查
I promise I'll weed them all out.
定当斩草除根
The Lin family will never rise again.
不会让林家有再起的机会
Benevolence.
慈悲为上
Benevolence first.
慈悲为上啊
Father.
父王
You're here, too, Mr. Wang.
王先生也在
Hail, Your Highness.
见过世子
What is it?
有什么事
(Zhao Xun, son of Jing'an) A student of Shangyin Academy
有上阴学宫学子
came to us with a ruse,
前来献策
and asks to see you.
求见父王
You personally introduced him?
你亲自引荐
I'm afraid
那学子说的话
what the student is going to say
怕是
happens to suit your will, right?
会与你不谋而合吧
Never mind.
算了
Bring him to me.
把他带过来吧
Yes.
是
Go.
去吧
It's flying towards North Liang?
飞去北椋的
Yes.
是
When someone gets the tassel,
有人收到剑穗
they will head to Qingzhou.
自然会赶到青州
At critical moments,
危急时
they will go to His Highness's aid.
为世子后援
What if
徐凤年
Xu Fengnian doesn't break into Qingyang Sect?
如果没有闯青阳派呢
If he doesn't break into Qingyang Sect,
世子若不曾闯青阳派
it means
就说明
he's discreet
是审时度势
and overcautious.
谨小慎微的性子
So he won't be in any major trouble
也就不会在青州
in Qingzhou.
有大麻烦
Therefore,
这支援兵
he won't be needing the aid.
也就不需要了
Does Xu Xiao
徐骁
even have to test his own son?
连自己的儿子都要这么试探
One's nature is only shown
临事关头
at pivotal moments.
方见本性
His Highness didn't let me down.
世子没有让我失望
He inherited the good qualities of Her Grace.
不愧是小姐的孩子
Old man,
老头
the boat moves so fast.
这船开得这么快
Can you catch any fish?
你钓得着鱼吗
Seriously?
这都行
Father.
父王
This is the student of Shangyin Academy.
这位就是上阴学宫来的学子
Zhao Kai.
赵楷
Hail, My Lord.
见过靖安王
You have a ruse for me?
你要献策
I've still got business to attend to.
王某还有事要做
I'll excuse myself out.
不如先行告辞
Stay here and listen, Mr. Wang.
王先生一起听一听
You can speak.
你说你的
You've been governing Qingzhou
靖安王入主青州
for nearly twenty years.
将近二十年载
Have you ever thought about
可曾想过
moving forward?
更进一步
What do you mean
你说的更进一步
by moving forward?
什么意思
The imperial court put you in Qingzhou
朝廷让靖安王入主青州
because they expected you to intimidate North Liang
是为了携青州水师之威
with the power of Qingzhou navy.
震慑北椋
If North Liang falls,
若北椋灭亡
it'll be your feat.
靖安王自是奇功一件
So you'll rise higher consequentially.
怎能不扶摇直上
North Liang has a 350,000-man army.
北椋三十五万大军
Who can do anything about that?
谁动得了
To destroy North Liang,
想灭北椋
a war isn't essential.
无需大战
You only have to kill one person.
杀一人即可
Who?
杀谁
Xu Fengnian.
徐凤年
You fish faster than a fishing net.
这钓鱼比捞鱼还快
I'm using the hook as a sword.
我这是借钓钩为剑
I'm not fishing but stabbing the fish.
这不是钓鱼而是刺鱼
You really are a great martial artist.
你武功真的很高
So-so.
还行吧
How great are you?
到底有多高
Want to call me Master?
想拜师了
Why can't you hold a sword?
为什么不能给你剑
Ever since I lost to Wang Xianzhi,
我败给王仙芝之后
I haven't held a sword.
我再未持剑
Xu Xiao thinks my heart
徐骁以为我心里面
is filled with humiliation and bellicosity
压了屈辱和战意
and that once I hold a sword,
他担心我一旦持剑
I'll lose control
会控制不住
and run amuck.
大开杀戒
Will you?
你会吗
No.
不会
Because what Xu Xiao doesn't know is, the reason I never hold a sword again
因为徐骁并不知道我不持剑
is not because of my defeat.
不是因为战败
Why, then?
那是为什么
It's because one person
那是因为有一个人
died before my eyes.
死在我眼前
A woman?
女人
Who was she?
她是你什么人啊
Jiang Ni.
姜泥
Do you know why I want you to be my disciple?
知道我为什么想收你为徒吗
Because I'm gifted.
因为我天赋很高啊
Not only that.
不仅仅是因为天赋
What else?
还有什么原因
You being around Xu Fengnian
你跟在徐凤年身边
is like
就像当年
she being around me back then.
她跟着我一样
I want to teach you swordsmanship
我想教你学剑
so that you can be better than Xu Fengnian.
是想让你的武功强过徐凤年
This way,
这样
he won't neglect you.
他就不会对你视而不见了
Even if someday,
就算有一天
he becomes as crazy as me,
这小子跟我一样疯了
you'll be able to keep him in check,
你也能治住他
preventing him from making
不让他犯下
unmendable mistakes.
难以弥补的大错
Are you saying the woman was…
你说的那个女人难道是被
She was killed by me.
是被我亲手杀死的
Father,
父王
what do you think?
您觉得呢
A load of fallacies.
妖言祸众罢了
But he's right.
可他说的没错啊
Once we kill Xu Fengnian,
杀了徐凤年
Xu Xiao will rebel.
徐骁必反
Xu Xiao's rebellion
徐骁反
isn't necessarily a bad thing.
未尝不是好事
The world would be in chaos.
天下大乱
What's good about that?
好处何在啊
Chaos needs to be handled.
大乱方能大治
And in the chaos,
乱世之中
you'll have the opportunity
王爷才有机会
to fight for
再去争一争
the throne.
那至尊之位啊
Kick him out of my mansion.
将他轰出府去
Father.
父王
If he enters the door again,
若再登门
he'll be decapitated and shown to the public.
斩首示众
The ambition
这孩子
in the kid's eyes
眼睛里的野心
is the same as mine back in the days.
和我当年一模一样
He was raised by you,
世子受王爷教诲
so he's undoubtedly aspirational.
自然少年有志
The kid that
我说的
I'm talking about is Zhao Kai.
是那位赵楷
What can he do no matter how ambitious he is?
野心再大他又有何用
But it happens that
可巧的是
his family name is Zhao, too.
他也姓赵
The Lin family
林家
hasn't been weeded out yet.
还没剿除干净
I'm off to the business.
王某就先告辞了
Do what you need to do, Mr. Wang.
王先生请便
Xu Fengnian
徐凤年
is about to arrive in Qingzhou.
就要到青州了
Are you really going to let him go?
王爷真要放了他
Be kind.
心有善念
Be benevolent.
慈悲为怀
Why did you agree to
那你又为什么会同意
send Xu Fengnian to Wudi City?
送徐凤年去武帝城
Enough.
好了
No more questions.
你别问了
I can tell others about the deal I made with Xu Xiao.
我跟徐骁的交易不能说与人听
Unless you're willing to be my disciple.
除非你愿意做我弟子
Whatever.
不听就不听
Are you ready?
那你准备好了吗
Ready for what?
准备什么啊
He's going to Wudi City.
他要去武帝城
It means you're going to confront Wang Xianzhi again.
那你恐怕又要对上王仙芝了呀
Pretty good.
挺好的
I've refrained myself for years,
我把自己关了这么多年
and I can really use a good fight.
手都痒了
There aren't many worthy opponents for me in the world.
天底下有资格与我交手的也没几个
Wang Xianzhi is the worthiest one.
王仙芝最合适了
Can you win?
你能赢吗
I'm not sure.
不好说啊
At the time,
当时
I lost by a neck.
输在毫厘之间
But now,
不过现在嘛
I may have gotten rusty because I haven't touched a sword for long.
许久没握剑有些手生
But that's okay.
不过也没关系
Fights are just for fun.
打架嘛 开心就好
Don't think about the result.
输赢先不想
I hope you win.
我希望你赢
Thank you, then.
那我谢谢你
Right now,
如今
no one is nice to me.
这世上没人对我好了
You're quite nice.
你还不错
What?
怎么了
Want
想
to call me Master?
拜我为师了
You can have it.
给你
I lend it to you.
借你的
Give it back to me right after the fight.
打完架立马还给我
You lend me the Divine Token?
你要把神符借给我
You recognize it?
你认识
I recognize it right away.
一眼就看出来了
The National Treasure of Chu State.
楚国至宝
You're just going to lend it to me like this?
你说借就借
It's just a dagger.
这就是把匕首
You're not going to run amuck, are you?
你不会又要大开杀戒吧
Don't worry.
你放心吧
I won't.
不会的
I owe you one.
算我欠你的
Think about
想想
how you want me to repay you.
要我怎么还
How about you give him some instructions?
要不你教教他吧
Is this how you want me to return the favor?
我的人情你就这么用了
It's your fault.
还不是怪你
Ever since you
自从那天晚上
blamed him that night,
你说了他几句之后
he hasn't allowed me to read the esoterica
他再也没让我读过秘籍
so I made a lot less money.
害我少赚好些钱
Maybe after this stage,
说不定过了这一关
he'll allow me to read again.
就又让我读书了呢
Whatever!
不去拉倒
Father has been living a comfortable life,
父王常年安逸
he's become conservative.
胆子都变小了
Killing the son of Lord of North Liang
没有京城旨意
without the imperial order
擅自杀北椋世子
is concerning indeed.
总有些顾虑
It's a golden opportunity.
大好的机会
We can't miss it.
放过了可不成
Filial piety is the No. 1 virtue.
百善孝为先
Your Highness,
世子
you should relieve His Lordship
该为王爷
from the worry.
解忧
Are you suggesting I do it?
你是说让我出手
I can.
也不是不行
It's just
只是
now that Xu Fengnian is out of North Liang,
徐凤年出了北椋
I'm afraid he's secured by top martial artists.
身边怕是有高手护卫
Your Highness.
世子
Look over there.
看那边
That guy?
就他
If you would like to clear Xu Fengnian's guards,
世子如果想除徐凤年身边护卫
he's your guy.
非他莫属
Kiddo.
小子
Sir?
前辈
Don't come over.
别过来
Don't bite me.
别咬我
Stop.
停一停
Don't sit there and watch.
别傻看着呀
Vajra, Bodhisattva, come back.
金刚菩萨回来
Vajra.
金刚
You two
你们两个
can't bite people.
别乱咬人
Senior is benevolent and kind.
也就是前辈宽宏大量
If he means to kill you, I can't stop him.
他要是动了杀心我可拦不住啊
You don't have to euphemistically beg for mercy.
别拐个弯儿求情了
I'm not that cruel
我还不至于
to harm these two little fellows.
对这两只小家伙动手呢
I thank you on behalf of them.
那我替它们谢谢您
You're quite a lucky guy.
你这小子也真是踩了狗屎啊
A few years later,
再过几年
I never planned to raise them into top fighters.
我收养他们没想着养成高手
People change.
人都会变的
You wanted to speak to me, Senior?
前辈找我有事
Practicing Dahuangting
光修大黄庭
without the martial moves
不练招式
is not going to take you anywhere.
一样是个废物
Draw Xiudong out of the scabbard.
绣冬出鞘
Are you going to instruct me?
前辈要指点我
Keep the blade above it.
刀横在上面
Too high.
太高
Good.
行
Flick the blade.
手指弹刀身
Try to smash the walnut.
试试砸碎核桃
Smash the walnut, but don't leave any traces on the deck.
碎核桃甲板不能留痕迹
Again.
再来
You read Compendium of Swords for nothing.
千剑草纲白看了
What's the balance of swordsmanship?
剑术剑道的平衡在哪里
Don't look at me like that.
看什么
I know it's a blade.
我知道你用的是刀
But the principle is the same.
可道理都一样
I just started reading Compendium of Swords,
千剑草纲就读了个开头
I didn't read too much.
没往下看啊
Why didn't you?
为什么不继续往下看
You said the book was ridiculous
那不是您说那书写的荒唐
and misleading.
误人子弟吗
Yeah.
是啊
Think about
那就想想那天
how I broke Fujiang Armor with a waterdrop.
我用水珠破红甲的场景
Think about how I flicked.
我那弹指是怎么运劲的
Hone your skills.
好好磨练吧
With your capability of comprehension,
就你这悟性
I doubt you can make it.
怕是够悬
Only smash the walnut.
只许碎一个核桃
No damage to any other stuff.
不要伤及其它
Do you know the Sword Tomb of the Wu family?
世子可知吴家剑冢
Of course, I do.
当然知道
A cradle of sword masters. A forbidden place.
剑仙辈出 人间禁地
There's a genius swordsman
吴家近几年
from the Wu family.
出了一名天才剑士
He left the Sword Tomb
二十岁
at the age of twenty
便出剑冢
to challenge swordsmen across the world
挑战天下剑士
and has never suffered a defeat.
从无败绩
The person
此位
(Sword Champion of Sword Tomb) is the new hope of the Wu family.
便是吴家新一代的希望
Wu Liuding.
吴六鼎
Are you finished?
说完了吗
I need to buy some salt.
我还要买盐
You're expecting Xu Fengnian
先生在青州
here in Qingzhou, aren't you?
是在等徐凤年吧
Does it have anything to do with you?
与你何干
The Mansion of Lord of Jing'an
靖安王府
offers to find Xu Fengnian's whereabouts for you.
愿为先生打探徐凤年行踪
You'll hear from us as soon as we get any information.
一有消息立时奉上
What do you want?
你想要什么
We only wish
能一睹先生出手
to watch you fight.
心满意足
Why would the Wu family attack Xu Fengnian?
这吴家人为什么对徐凤年出手
Xu Fengnian's mother
徐凤年的母亲
once left the Sword Tomb for Xu Xiao.
曾为徐骁反出剑冢
Now, the new generation
如今新一代
came to settle the score.
算旧账来了
Still practicing?
还在练呢
A reminder for you.
给你提个醒啊
If you succeed a few days later,
过几天要是练成了
stack one walnut on another,
记得叠两枚核桃
and then…
然后呢
And then flick the blade,
然后弹刀下去
smash the walnut,
核桃俱碎
make sure the deck is fine.
船板没事
I've done it.
我已经做到了
How is it possible?
怎么可能
You started practicing from noon.
中午才练的
Don't lie to me.
你可别骗我啊
You're quite talented.
你小子倒是有点悟性
Then why are you sitting here?
那你坐这儿发什么愣
I'd like to try three walnuts.
我想试试三枚
I tried several times,
但试了好几次
but I never made it.
都没成功
When I flicked the blade,
用力的时候
the walnut at the bottom
最下面那一枚
would be struck away.
会被弹开
Is two the limit?
难道说两枚就是极限了
Do you know the difference
知道
between Sword Move and Sword Intent?
剑招和剑意的区别吗
Blade.
刀
The blade didn't move a bit.
刀没动
How did the walnut break?
怎么碎的
This is Sword Gust.
这便是剑罡
It won't work only by watching.
光看没用
Hold Chunlei below Xiudong.
把春雷悬在绣冬下
Feel carefully
细心感受
what Sword Gust is.
何为剑罡
I felt it.
感受到了
It was a strong gust.
是气劲凌空
An inner force breaks out of the body
内息破体
through a weapon.
透兵刃而出
The essence of Sword Gust is the utilization of genuine spirit.
剑罡本质上就是真气的运用
Based on your level of Dahuangting,
以你大黄庭的功底
after several practices,
多练几次
you can do it, too.
也能试出来
Sword Gust is way more powerful than sword Move.
那这剑罡可比剑招厉害多了
Sword Move can't do that.
剑招可没这效果
Hold the blades in place again.
刀再放
It felt different.
这次又有不同
It felt like a force hit the blade
好像有力道击打
to make Chunlei break away from me.
逼迫春雷脱手
This is Sword Move.
这就是剑招
Touch the face of Xiudong.
你摸一下绣冬的刀面
It felt like it didn't move,
感觉没动
but actually, there are slight tremors.
但其实有细微震动
At the second flick,
第二指击打
it seemed Xiudong didn't move,
绣冬看似未动
but it bent
其实已经以极快的速度
at an amazingly fast speed
弯曲六次
and hit Chunlei six times.
击打春雷
The counterforce got it back to normal.
然后再借力恢复正常
It bent six times?
弯曲六次
I didn't see anything.
都没看出来
Good Sword Move
上乘剑招
is as fast as thunder and as steady as mountain.
快入奔雷 稳如五岳
Boy,
小子
you've still got much to learn.
你要学的还多着呢
Sword Move and Sword Gust.
那这剑招与剑罡
Which is stronger?
孰强孰弱
If I break an enemy with Sword Gust, then Sword Gust is better.
老夫以剑罡破敌便是剑罡厉害
If I kill someone with Sword Move,
老夫用剑招杀人
then Sword Move beats every Sword Gust in the world.
剑招
I get it.
明白了
You're the best.
您最厉害
You're indeed clever.
你果然有悟性
Sword Move, Sword Gust.
剑招 剑罡
You work on them yourself.
自己琢磨
Soon, we'll arrive in Qingzhou.
不几日便到青州
I won't fight unless necessary.
不到万不得已老夫懒得出手
Whether you can dodge all the menaces or not
能不能躲过明刀暗箭
will be up to you.
看你自己了
Thank you for your instructions, sir.
多谢前辈指点
I didn't mean to instruct you.
我没想指点你
I owe someone a favor.
是欠了人情
And I'm returning it by instructing you.
拿你来还
You owe a favor to whom?
谁能让您欠人情啊
An inner force breaks out of the body
内息破体
through a weapon.
透兵刃而出
Sir,
前辈
I managed to perform Sword Gust.
我练出剑罡了
That's true.
有道理
Your strength
就这么点力气
wasn't even enough to kill a chicken.
杀只鸡都不够
Keep practicing.
慢慢磨练吧
The kid
这小怪物
improves faster than I did.
修行的速度比老夫当年还快
General,
将军
you've slept several nights
你已经在王府门口
in front of the mansion.
睡了好几日了
Your people want to know
府里的人都问您
when you will be back at home.
什么时候回去呢
Godfather
义父
asked me to wait for a hawk to deliver a tassel.
让我在这等着鹞鹰送剑穗
I won't leave
鹰不来
until the hawk comes.
我不走
What is that?
那是什么呀
A hawk.
鹞鹰
It seems like a hawk.
好像是鹞鹰
General.
将军
I'll go check it for you.
我去替你瞧瞧
Move aside.
闪开
General, be careful.
将军小心
The tassel.
是剑穗
It's the tassel!
真是剑穗
You stay in front of the mansion.
你
Once you receive the tassel from a hawk,
一旦收到了鹞鹰送来的剑穗
you lead your cavalrymen to Qingzhou at once.
你立刻率领本部骑兵赶往青州
General, take it easy.
将军
Pass my order. We set out.
传令拔营
Follow me to the east to reinforce His Highness.
随我东行接应世子
The dispatchment of soldiers require the tiger tally.
调兵需有虎符
The heck with the tiger tally.
虎你个鬼啊
I'll execute all those who disobey me.
不去的都砍了
Please put on your armor, General.
将军请换甲胄
I'll put on it on the way.
路上换 路上换
Make way. Make way.
闪开 闪开
Words from the river,
江上传来消息
Xu Fengnian will arrive at Chunshen Lake today.
徐凤年今日便到春神湖
Have you let Wu Liuding know?
吴六鼎通知了吗
He said he's doing sword maintenance
他说要养剑
and won't take action until tomorrow.
明日才肯动手
We won't wait for him.
不等了
Rally the navy and set sail to Chunshen Lake.
先调集水师赶往春神湖
We can't miss the opportunity.
机不可失
You gave the Divine Token to Senior Li?
你把神符给李前辈了
It's none of your business.
关你什么事
Aren't you afraid of falling into the water?
你不怕摔下去啊
I get nice views here.
这风景好
How about you try to sit here, too?
要不坐下试试
I'm a bad swimmer.
我水性不好
I'm here with you.
有我在
You won't fall into the water.
掉不下去
The lake is way larger than the one in the mansion.
这湖比府里的大多了
Of course.
那可没法比
800-long Chunshen Lake
八百里春神湖
is where many waterways and rivers rendezvous.
容纳天下水路吞吐大江
It's always been a strategic location.
历来是兵家死争之地
The Lord of Jing'an governs Qingzhou
靖安王坐镇青州
and his navy is entrenched in Chunshen Lake.
养水师盘踞春神湖
It's his natural defense from North Liang.
就是借天险拒北椋
You don't find another lake like this
这等大湖就是放在天下
across the entire world.
也是独树一帜
You talk so much.
啰嗦得要死
What do you want to speak to me?
你找我有事
Your Hukui babies
你那两只小虎夔
are stealing raw meat from the provision cabin.
在储物舱偷生肉
They didn't hurt anyone, right?
没伤人吧
No.
那倒没有
They are very slick.
小家伙鬼得很
They scare others but never hurt anyone.
只吓人不伤人
Leave them be, then.
那就不管它们
There's a ship over there.
前面有船
And another ship behind us.
那后面也有一艘
That's a big one.
好大的船
Those are Qingzhou navy's Yellow Dragon Towered Ships.
这些都是青州水师的黄龙楼船
They came to look for trouble?
找麻烦的
Maybe.
或许吧
I see a ship over there.
那边有艘船
It's fine.
没关系
That's Qingzhou navy, too.
那也是青州水师
Do you think
世子以为
it's a coincidence
这艘船是巧遇
or an arrangement?
还是专程出现
It must be a coincidence.
定是巧合
I heard nothing from the Mansion of the Lord of Jing'an,
靖安王府未出声
so who in Qingzhou dare come to pick Xu Fengnian up?
青州城谁敢来接徐凤年
What does this ship want?
这艘又是干吗来的
Weird.
奇了怪了
It seems that ship is here to pick Xu Fengnian up.
好像真是去接徐凤年的
Who dare pick him up?
谁这么大胆子
Do you know him?
认识吗
Wang Linquan?
王林泉
Are we going to fight them?
这是要动手吗
Are you
阁下
the son of the Lord of North Liang, Xu Fengnian?
可是北椋世子徐凤年
Yes, I am.
正是
Your Highness.
世子
Did His Lordship ask
这位王先生此时出现
Mr. Wang to appear at this moment?
是王爷的意思
Your Highness.
世子
Turn back to the base.
调头回营
We can't attack them today
今日不能出手
in case that Father's plan is disrupted.
免得坏了父王的谋划
Look so alike.
像
Who on earth are you?
你到底是谁
I'm Wang Linquan.
老奴 王林泉
Hail, Your Highness.
见过世子
Wang Linquan?
王林泉
You're the money-maker under the Lord of Jing'an?
你是靖安王麾下那个财神爷
I was ordered to
投效靖安王
serve under the Lord of Jing'an.
不过是奉命行事
I used to be a servant of North Liang.
老奴实为北椋旧部
It was His Lordship's order
王林泉投靠青州
that Wang Linquan went to serve under Qingzhou.
本就是王爷安排
You know him?
你认识
I've been the secret liaison
这些年就是我暗中联络
between North Liang and Wang Linquan.
与王林泉联系
So it was Xu Xiao who sent you to Qingzhou?
所以是徐骁派你来青州的
Yes.
是
After decades of endeavors
数十年经营
and the secret help of General-in-Chief,
也是大将军暗中相助
the Lord of Jing'an has put his trust in me.
靖安王最后是信了老奴
The Lin family fell
林家覆灭
and the financial power of Qingzhou was given to me.
青州的财权就交到老奴手上了
The Lord of Jing'an thinks he's the winner of the game,
靖安王自以为棋局大胜
but eventually,
可到头来
it is General-in-Chief who gets the better of him.
还是大将军棋高一招
Decades of the under-cover job must have been tough for you.
这么多年潜伏何其不易
As you kneel, all of your previous hard work goes in vain.
你这么一跪就前功尽弃了
The day you arrive in Qingzhou
世子到青州之日
is the day my identity as a liegeman of North Liang gets reinstated.
便是老奴恢复北椋军身份之时
I've been
这一天
waiting for this day for too long.
老奴等了太久了
For too long.
太久了
Let's not talk about it.
咱不说这些了
There's an island in the middle of Chunshen Lake
在春神湖中心它有一个岛屿
named
名叫
Mount Mu.
姥山
It's been under my control long ago.
它早就在老夫的掌控之下
Your Highness,
世子
please follow me.
请随我来
Turn the helm.
转舵
Go home.
回家
How many more tricks
徐骁究竟还有多少暗棋
is Xu Xiao playing behind my back?
没让我知道